<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The case of William Eyres, esq. concerning his estate in Ireland, truly stated and humbly presented to the kings most excellent Majesty and both Houses of Parliament.</title>
            <author>Eyre, William, of Shelelah, Ireland.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1675</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 36 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 9 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B09133</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing E3943B</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R207977</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">61297020</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 61297020</idno>
            <idno type="VID">180573</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B09133)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 180573)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2834:14)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The case of William Eyres, esq. concerning his estate in Ireland, truly stated and humbly presented to the kings most excellent Majesty and both Houses of Parliament.</title>
                  <author>Eyre, William, of Shelelah, Ireland.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>16 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <p>
                     <name type="place">[London : s.n.,</name>
                     <date>1675]</date>
                  </p>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Attributed to William Eyre. Cf. Wing (2nd ed.).</note>
                  <note>Place and date of publication suggested by Wing (2nd ed.).</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: Henry E. Huntington Library and Art Gallery.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Eyre, William, --  of Shelelah, Ireland --  Estate.</term>
               <term>England and Wales. --  Sovereign (1660-1685 : Charles II).</term>
               <term>England and Wales. --  Parliament.</term>
               <term>Decendants' estates --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-06</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-06</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-07</date>
            <label>Olivia Bottum</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-07</date>
            <label>Olivia Bottum</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:180573:1"/>
            <head>THE CASE OF William Eyres Eſq.</head>
            <head type="sub">Concerning his Eſtate in <hi>Ireland,</hi> truly ſtated, and Humbly Preſented to the Kings moſt excellent Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſty, and both Houſes of Parliament.</head>
            <p>
               <hi>CAlcot Chambre</hi> 
               <abbr>Eſq</abbr> being ſeized in Fee of the half Barony of <hi>Shelelah</hi> with the Caſtle of <hi>Carnow,</hi> and Appurtenan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces thereunto belonging, in the County of <hi>Wicklow</hi> in the Kingdom of <hi>Ireland;</hi> conteyning of Arable, Paſture, Meadows, and Wood-lands, about ſixty thouſand Acres. Fearing the profuſeneſs of his Son, made a Leaſe of the ſame, <hi>Anno.</hi> 1629. To <hi>James Fines, Nathaniel Fines,</hi> and <hi>John Crew,</hi> 
               <abbr>Eſq</abbr> for two hundred years without Impeachment of waſt, in truſt for payment of his Debts and Legacies; and afterwards to ſuch uſes as he ſhould declare by any further Deed, or by his laſt Will and Teſtament; and for default of ſuch Declaration to the uſe of his own right Heirs.</p>
            <p>The ſaid <hi>Calcot Chambre Anno.</hi> 1635. Made his laſt Will, and gave all his ſaid Lands to his only Son <hi>Calcot Chambre;</hi> as alſo
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:180573:2"/>all his Goods and Chattels: and made his ſaid Son Sole Executor, and dyed.</p>
            <p>After whoſe death, the ſaid Truſtees poſſeſt themſelves of the Premiſes, and would have let a Leaſe thereof to one <hi>Sandford</hi> for three years, for payment of the <hi>Deceaſed's</hi> Debts and Legacies; and to allow Young <hi>Chambre</hi> 300 <abbr>
                  <hi>ll.</hi>
               </abbr> 
               <hi>per Annum</hi> for thoſe three years, and then to account and deliver up the Eſtate to him: For this <hi>Sandford</hi> Marrying Old <hi>Chambre</hi>'s Daughter did manage the Eſtate in <hi>his</hi> time, and therefore the Truſtees thought him the fitter to manage it now for the Young Man. The rather for that the greater part of the ſaid Debts and Legacies was due to him and his Brother in Law the Lord <hi>Brobſon,</hi> ſince Earl of <hi>Meeth,</hi> who Married Old <hi>Chambre</hi>'s other Daughter.</p>
            <p>That <hi>Thomas</hi> late Earl of <hi>Strafford</hi> then Lord Deputy of <hi>Ire<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> being by ſome ill Perſons put upon coveting this Eſtate, (which was, and is, as conſiderable as moſt in that Kingdom) prevented the Truſtees in theſe their honeſt Intentions, and at laſt got the ſame into his own hands, or in truſt for him, by the means and Practices following.</p>
            <p>The aforeſaid Young <hi>Chambre</hi> being come to <hi>Dublin</hi> with his Wife to take Shipping for <hi>England</hi> to live with his Father in Law <abbr>Eſq</abbr> 
               <hi>Leſter</hi> in <hi>Cheſhire,</hi> and there abide 'till the aforeſaid three years were expired, was by the ſubtilty of the Earl of <hi>Straffora's</hi> Agents perſwaded not to go Aboard that night, but uſe means to get his Brother <hi>Sandford</hi> out of the Eſtate, or elſe he would be un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>done: And that he ſhould Arreſt his Brother <hi>Sandford</hi> for ſeven thouſand Pounds, which he was to give an account for in his Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers time: But the morning following <hi>Chambre</hi> himſelf was made a Priſoner for the mourning for his Fathers Funeral; and <hi>Sandford</hi> hearing of it, Poſted to <hi>Dublin</hi> to pay the Debt: But the before mentioned Agents met him as ſoon as he came, and told him if he went to his Brother he would be Arreſted for ſeven thouſand Pounds. Upon which <hi>Sandford,</hi> being much troubled,
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:180573:2"/>went back and took counſel of the Earl of <hi>Strafford,</hi> ſeeming his great Friend, whom he did not ſuſpect to have any deſign upon the Eſtate: and he adviſed inſtead of releaſing his Brother, to clap another Arreſt upon him for a thouſand Pounds Legacy that his Father gave him. When this was done, the Earl cauſed Sir <hi>Philip Perſival,</hi> and others, to make a Propoſal; that the ſaid Sir <hi>Philip</hi> might have a Leaſe of 22 years of <hi>Chambres</hi> Eſtate, for the uſe of the Counteſs of <hi>Carlile,</hi> paying 4000. <abbr>
                  <hi>l.</hi>
               </abbr> Fine, and 500. <hi>per Annum;</hi> and the third Penny profit of the Wood And in order to this, the ſaid Agents perſwaded <hi>Chambre</hi> to Petition the Earl of <hi>Strafford,</hi> that the Leaſe the Truſtees would make to <hi>Sandford</hi> might not go on; but that this Leaſe proffered by Sir <hi>Philip</hi> might be perfected, that he might receive the 4000. <abbr>
                  <hi>l.</hi>
               </abbr> to pay his Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers Debts and Legacies, and get out of Priſon. As ſoon as e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver the Earl of <hi>Strafford</hi> received the Petition, he tranſmitted it to <hi>England</hi> to the late King and Counſel; and encloſed it in a Letter to Secretary <hi>Nickolas,</hi> ſeeming to commiſerate the condition of the Priſoner, and troubled that they being out of his reach, he could not redeem the poor Man; and therefore deſired that the Truſtees might be Summoned before the King and Counſel, to anſwer the Petition; or elſe to be ſent over into <hi>Ireland,</hi> that he might take a courſe with them, and the Defendant <hi>Sandford,</hi> that the Priſoner might be releaſed.</p>
            <p>Hereupon the Truſtees were immediately ſent for to Counſel-Board to yeild to the Leaſe propounded to <hi>Perſival;</hi> who alledg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing that they were letting a Leaſe to <hi>Sandford,</hi> Brother in Law to the Petitioner, that was much more advantagious to the Petiti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>oner, than that propounded by <hi>Perſival.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The King and Counſel made an Order, <hi>that the buſineſs ſhould be wholly remitted to the Earl of</hi> Strafford, <hi>to perfect that Leaſe for the Counteſs of</hi> Carliſle (which was in truth for himſelf, as did afterwards appear:) <hi>Or make any other better Bargain for the good of the Petitioner; declaring the Earl of</hi> Strafford <hi>ſhould by a
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:180573:3"/>Decree in Chancery inforce the Truſtees, to aſſent to what Bargain he ſhould make with the ſaid Counteſs, or others, ſo far as did concern their truſt for twenty two years.</hi> And farther, <hi>that the Earl ſhould provide by ſuch Decree, to preſerve the Inheritance, according to the intent of Old</hi> Chambre; (which was, that the truſt ſhould continue in them 200 years: for he made a power in the Leaſe to revoke it, but never did it; ſo that it is the general Judgement of Counſel, that the Leaſe is ſtill in being, and diſtinct from the Inheritance.)</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Calcot Chambre</hi> being informed what order the Earl of <hi>Strafford</hi> had received Petitions again to him and the Counſel, that the Leaſe propounded by <hi>Perſivall</hi> might not be made good, for he could have a great deal better bargain. At the Reading of which, his Brother in Law the Lord <hi>Brobſon</hi> being one of the Counſel, deſired, ſeeing his Brother muſt be forced to Lett his Eſtate to pay his Debts, that the King and Counſels Order might be fulfilled, and the beſt Bargain accepted of; The moſt of his Fathers Debts being due to him who there offered to have the Leaſe of 22 years, and give his Brother 5000 <abbr>
                  <hi>l.</hi>
               </abbr> Fine, and 600 <abbr>
                  <hi>ll.</hi>
               </abbr> 
               <hi>per An.</hi> And half the Profits of the Wood: whereas <hi>Perſivall</hi> would give but 4000 <abbr>
                  <hi>ll.</hi>
               </abbr> fine and 500 <abbr>
                  <hi>ll.</hi>
               </abbr> 
               <hi>per An.</hi> and the third penny profit of the Woods: ſo that here was a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bove ten thouſand pounds profit, better than that of <hi>Perſivalls;</hi> For there was above two thouſand pounds a year made of the Woods, beſides a thouſand pounds a year of an Iron work upon the Ground: Yet, notwithſtand <hi>Strafford</hi> had the Kings Order to make the <hi>beſt</hi> Bargain for the Petitioner, he refuſed this of the Lord <hi>Brobſons,</hi> and cauſeth that of <hi>Perſivals</hi> to be perfected by a ſpecial Order of him and his Counſel: Then <hi>Sandford</hi> was turned out, and the Earle of <hi>Straffords</hi> Agents got poſſeſſion of the Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſes: Yet ſtill <hi>Chambre</hi> was deteyned a Priſoner, though <hi>Sandford</hi> and others Releaſed him; but many came againſt him with Paper Petitions to the Earle of <hi>Strafford,</hi> inſomuch Mr. <hi>Chambre</hi> could ſcarce get Victuals, and often Petitioned to the Earle of <hi>Strafford</hi>
               <pb n="5" facs="tcp:180573:3"/>that the 4000 <abbr>
                  <hi>ll.</hi>
               </abbr> Fine might be paid, that he might be able to pay his Debts and go out of Priſon; upon which, the Earle cauſes an Agent to go to him, and tell him the 4000 <abbr>
                  <hi>ll.</hi>
               </abbr> would not pay his Debts, and perſwaded him to ſell the Reverſion of the Eſtate, and he ſhould have 13 thouſand 200 pounds for it: that is to ſay, 1200 pounds in hand to help to pay his Debts, and with the other twelve thouſand pounds the Earle would Purchaſe him a better Eſtate than his was: But <hi>Chambre</hi> alledging he could not ſell it becauſe of the Leaſe of two hundred years, was kept cloſer Priſoner than before, and forced to Petition to the Earle, that the Cook might be paid that he might have Victuals.</p>
            <p>And ſome of the Earls Agents came often unto him in Priſon to make him merry and cheerful; and then when they found him a little yielding to the Earls deſires, he ſhould be ſent for to Dine with him at the Caſtle, and ſometimes let him out of Priſon, and then one pretended Debt or other clapt him up again; inſomuch that he was brought into ſuch miſery that he was willing to yield to the Earls deſire, If his Wife would: Then the Earle ſent a Meſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſenger to his Wife, deſiring her that ſhe would paſs a Fine and Recovery, that her Husband might ſell his Eſtate and come out of Priſon; but ſhe refuſing, was threatned, and her Husband kept cloſe Priſoner, that ſhe, nor any elſe ſhould come at him, though ſhe ſix times Petitioned to ſee him, but could not be admitted, 'till he falling often into Convulſion Fits, the Keeper thinking he would have died, went to the Earl of <hi>Strafford,</hi> and told him that Mr. <hi>Chambre</hi> had a deſire to ſee his Wife, and if ſhe did not ſee him ſpeedily, ſhe would never ſee him alive; upon which he ſent his Gentleman to go along with her, and three other men went into his Chamber with her, which are all ſworn to what followeth, That he lay upon the Table on his belly as good as dead, and they ſetting him upon his Breech, pouring ſome Spirits, and rubbing his Temples, he began to look up, and his Wife weeping, ſaid Huſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>band, how doſt thou do: Wife, ſaid he, I am kept here for a
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:180573:4"/>Bargain: prethe Husband, replyed ſhe, pardon me, for it is my fault I would not paſs a Fine of Recovery: but rather than I will be an Inſtrument to thy death, I will Signe it.</p>
            <p>Upon which words the Gentleman returned to the Earl, and told him he muſt ſtrike whileſt the Irons were hot, for now ſhe was willing: So a Fine was perfected upon theſe words only, and a Deed Sealed by <hi>Chambres</hi> for the Reverſion only to four perſons, <hi>Carpenter, Car, Little,</hi> and <hi>Billingsly,</hi> for 13 thouſand two hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred pounds, when the Eſtate was worth above Six ſcore thouſand; for the Lands would be worth, within 4 or 5 years time, when the old Leaſes expired, 5 or ſix thouſand pounds <hi>per Ann.</hi> and at that time the Wood upon the Eſtate was worth a hundred thouſand pounds, the Earl of <hi>Corke</hi> having proffered (but a year before Old <hi>Chambre</hi>'s death) Threeſcore thouſand pounds for the Timber Trees upon the Land.</p>
            <p>But how Wood, and Land, and all muſt go for Thirteen thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſand two hundred pounds, and even of that Money, none was ever yet paid, except one Five hundred pounds, which I think was to <hi>Chambres</hi> of <hi>Minmore,</hi> for to relinquiſh all his Right in the Premi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes, ſo much being given him by Old Mr. <hi>Chambres</hi> Will, to Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>linquiſh all Rights, and Claimes in the Premiſes. And the Earl of <hi>Strafford</hi> made above 30 thouſand pounds out of the Profits of the Eſtate in four years time, before the Rebellion broak forth in <hi>Ireland,</hi> as hath been proved by many Witneſſes. Whereby ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pears how well the Kings Order before mentionod was obſerved, that the <hi>beſt Bargain</hi> ſhould be made to preſerve the Eſtate, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>This being done, the ſaid <hi>Chambre</hi> was ſet at Liberty, but com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing into the freſh Air, and a full Dyet, he lived not long after, leaving two Children, a Son, (that dyed ſoon after him) and a Daughter.</p>
            <p>But before his Death, <hi>viz.</hi> the 7th of <hi>Aug.</hi> 1638. he makes his laſt Will and Teſtament, bequeathing all his Lands to <hi>Mary</hi> his Wife, for 12 years, the Remainder one Moiety to his ſaid Wife,
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:180573:4"/>during her life, the other Moiety to his Heirs-Male, and for want of an Heir-Male, to his Uncle <hi>Chambre</hi> of <hi>Minmore,</hi> and his Heirs-male for ever: And 2000 <abbr>
                  <hi>ll.</hi>
               </abbr> to his Daughter: And makes his Wife ſole Executrix, and expreſsly gave her all his Goods and Chattels: By which ſhe became Entituled to the Leaſe of 200 years, and the 13200 <abbr>
                  <hi>ll.</hi>
               </abbr> agreed to be given for the Reverſion of the Premiſes.</p>
            <p>But <hi>Chambre</hi> thus dying, without having Signed any Deed to lead the uſes of the ſaid Fine, the Lord Deputy, apprehending he had not yet made the Eſtate ſecure, by his Agents ſets up a Nuncupative Will of the ſaid <hi>Chambre,</hi> and a Deed of Uſes thereupon, bearing Date the 3d of <hi>Novemb.</hi> with Feoffees joyn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing with the ſaid <hi>Chambre:</hi> that is to ſay, <hi>Ralph Leſter, Job Ward, Calcot Chambre</hi> of <hi>Minmore,</hi> 
               <abbr>Eſq</abbr> pretended to be made his Feo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ffees by a Deed in his Life time, and a Leaſe, and Releaſe dated the ſame day under <hi>Chambre</hi> of <hi>Carnow</hi>'s hand only, of all the Lands and Appurtinences abſolutely, whereas the ſaid <hi>Chambre</hi> in truth did perfect in his Life time only one Deed Dated the 2d of <hi>Novemb.</hi> which was only of the Reverſion, and without any Feo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ffees joyning: And theſe After-deeds were ſet up only to make the buſineſs plauſible on the Earls ſide.</p>
            <p>For the ſame 3d of <hi>Novemb. Carpenter, Car, Little,</hi> and <hi>Billingſly</hi> made a Deed back to <hi>Calcot Chambre</hi> of <hi>Carnow,</hi> and to <hi>Leſter, Ward</hi> and <hi>Chambre</hi> of <hi>Linmore</hi> and their Heirs of all their Right and Title, till the Deed of Uſes, or Articles of Agreement were made good by <hi>Carpenter, Car, Little,</hi> and <hi>Billingſly,</hi> but all to the uſes of the Nuncupative Will: ſo that if we own theſe Deeds, we muſt own that (which is falſe) and if we Sue <hi>Car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>penter,</hi> &amp;c. who Purchaſed of <hi>Chambre,</hi> they Anſwer, they Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>convey'd all the Right they Purchaſed, and we may ſeize the Lands for not making good the Articles, and renounce all Title.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>In which lies the grand Intrigue of the Fraud.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>But to the end if one Device would not ſerve, another might, the
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:180573:5"/>Earl about <hi>Trinity</hi> Term 13 <hi>Car. Prim.</hi> cauſed a Caſe, common<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly called the Caſe of Tenures upon defective Titles to be made, without Jury or Tryal, or conſent of Parties, or other legal proceſs, and procured the opinion of the Judges of <hi>England,</hi> and Letters Pattents: wherein (amongſt others) this Eſtate of <hi>Shalelaw</hi> is mentioned, as a defective Title (though it never were ſo; as by inquiſition upon Record appears) and upon that he obtained an Act of Parliament in <hi>Ireland</hi> in 1640. (As is pretended by the now Earl of <hi>Strafford</hi>) for confirmation of Eſtates on defective Ti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tles; amongſt which this was again inſerted: But this Act was never Recorded; for before he obtained the Royal Aſſent he was put to Death.</p>
            <p>But before that, the Truſtees in the Leaſe of 200 years by vexation and practiſe were prevailed upon to Aſſign the ſaid Leaſe (contrary to their truſt, and without <hi>Chambre</hi>'s Widdow joyn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing with them) to two Perſons for the uſe of <hi>Carpenter, Carr,</hi> and others: But it was upon condition that the 13200 <abbr>
                  <hi>l.</hi>
               </abbr> ſhould be paid, or laid out for purchaſing Land of Inheritance according to the aforeſaid Articles.</p>
            <p>Which Articles were to be performed in 1645. but were ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver made good, nor can be. True it is in the time of the Suits with the Truſtees, the Earl of <hi>Strafford</hi> pretended for to purchaſe a place, called the <hi>Rannalaws</hi> of Sir <hi>Adam Loftus,</hi> which was Plantation Land, taken from the <hi>Iriſh</hi> in <hi>Ireland,</hi> and given to ſeveral men, upon commiſſion of Grace, and no real Inheritance, according to the Articles: and the Purchaſe was but a Leaſe of five hundred years, to the uſe of Mr. <hi>Chambre,</hi> and the aforeſaid Truſtees, which was mentioned in the ſaid Articles, for ſuch damages as they ſhould ſuſtain, till the Articles of agreement was made good, on <hi>Carpenter</hi> and <hi>Cars</hi> part.</p>
            <p>And alſo the Leaſe of five hundred years, was for the uſe of <hi>Carpenter</hi> and <hi>Car</hi> till the other ſhould be made good the Articles on their part.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="9" facs="tcp:180573:5"/>
The Earl of <hi>Strafford</hi>'s Agents pretend they have laid out ten thouſand Pounds for it, but they laid it out without our aſſent; for the Land was never worth five thouſand Pounds, as it ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>peared by many Witneſſes: and the ſaid <hi>Mary Chambre</hi> the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lict (then Married to <hi>Job Ward</hi>) was put into Poſſeſſion of it, not knowing where elſe to go; and injoyed it one year, before the Rebellion broke out, as part of ſecurity of the twelve thouſand Pounds, which ſhould be laid out for Land of Inheritance.</p>
            <p>It is to be noted, that all this while, the real Will in Writing of <hi>Chambre</hi> was not diſcovered, he having intruſted it with Mr. <hi>Guttridge</hi> then Miniſter of <hi>Carnow;</hi> who in the year 1640. proved the ſaid Will, and <hi>Mary</hi> the Relict came in Perſon and Admini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtred to it; and then tho Nuncupative Will was thrown out of Court, although ſhe was forced to Adminiſter to it a year before: And the Earl of <hi>Strafford</hi> had ſpent above 500. <abbr>
                  <hi>l.</hi>
               </abbr> in the maintain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of it in Law; but when this was done, the Earl of <hi>Strafford,</hi> and his Agents, was at a ſtand, becauſe all the falſe Deeds and the Articles of agreement upon which the Truſtees ſigned away their truſt; and whatſoever was done upon the nuncupidie Will, was void and out of doors: And <hi>Job Ward</hi> and his Wife had all the Deeds and Writings and the Leaſe of 200 years (that was re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſigned up by Mr. <hi>Crew</hi>) in their own hands, and none were de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>livered to the Earl of <hi>Strafford</hi> or his Agents; becauſe the pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving of the real Will had hindered any farther proceedings at preſent.</p>
            <p>And in the time of the Rebellion <hi>Job Ward</hi> and his Wife was turned out of the <hi>Ranalows</hi> by the Rebbells, and came into <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land</hi> and lived ſome years. and <hi>Job Ward</hi> dyed.</p>
            <p>And in the year 1647. <hi>William Eyres</hi> Marries the Widdow; by which Marriage all the Writing and proceedings in the cauſe aboveſaid, came to his hands; and alſo the Leaſe of 200 years, and the Eſtate therein: but by deceit and ſubtilty he was deprived of them, and many of them came into the now Earl of <hi>Strafford</hi>'s hands, and his Agents. For,</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="10" facs="tcp:180573:6"/>
By the means of the ſaid <hi>Eyres</hi> often Impriſonment oppoſing <hi>Oliver Cromwel</hi> in his Arbittrary power, and the death of the late King of bleſſed Memory, the ſaid <hi>Eyres</hi> being a cloſe Priſoner in <hi>Warwick</hi> Caſtle in the year 1649. Judge Advocate <hi>Whale,</hi> being a Servant to Mrs. <hi>Chambre</hi> in <hi>Ireland</hi> (which was become <hi>Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liam Eyres</hi> his Wife) he perſwaded her to make Colonel <hi>James Temple</hi> his Daughters Guardian; for <hi>Cromwel</hi> would ſequeſter her Eſtate, becauſe of her Husbands Actions: whoſe pernicious advice ſhe took, and alſo truſted the ſaid <hi>Temple</hi> with moſt of the Writings concerning the Eſtate, upon his promiſe, to reſtore her Daughter, and Writings, upon demand: But the ſaid <hi>Eyres</hi> and his Wife in the year 1650. demanded the Daughter, and Wri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tings, which he refuſed to deliver; and contrary to his promiſes Inveigles the Daughter to marry with his youngeſt Son <hi>Alexander:</hi> and the ſaid <hi>Eyres,</hi> the latter end of the year 1650. went into <hi>Ireland</hi> to look after his Eſtate, in the right of his Wife; and the then Lord <hi>Ierton,</hi> being informed by moſt of the Nobility and Gentry, of the wrong done to Mr. <hi>Chambre,</hi> the ſaid <hi>Eyres,</hi> his prediceſſor by the late Earl of <hi>Strafford,</hi> did, by the advice of the then Counſel put the ſaid <hi>Eyres</hi> in <hi>poſſeſſion</hi> of the ſaid <hi>Chambre's</hi> Eſtate with the Caſtle of <hi>Carnow,</hi> which the ſaid <hi>Eyres</hi> held ſeve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral years; but being made Priſoner again, by <hi>Cromwel,</hi> for many years together. The Earl of <hi>Strafford,</hi> and Colonel <hi>James Temple,</hi> and his Son <hi>Alexander</hi> and his Wife, taking the opportunity of <hi>Eyre's</hi> Impriſonment, combined together, and commenced many Suits to out him of the half Barony of <hi>Shelela,</hi> of which he was in poſſeſſion, and entertained one Mr. <hi>Joſeph Avery</hi> to proſecute both their Suits againſt him; and truſted him with the Writings, which Old <hi>Temple</hi> had betrayed <hi>Eyres of.</hi> And alſo delivered the Leaſe of 200 years in to my Lord <hi>Crews</hi> hands (who was one of the Truſtees) who hath ſworn he hath the Leaſe ſtill by him; and ſhall deliver it, to whom a Court ſhall command.</p>
            <p>The firſt Suit the ſaid <hi>Avery,</hi> and the Earl of <hi>Strafford</hi> his Agents
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:180573:6"/>commenced, was in the behalf of the Counteſs of <hi>Carlile</hi> for the Leaſe aforeſaid for 22 years; yet had not paid a Penny Rent, nor any profit of the Wood, according to the tenour of the Leaſe; upon which the Leaſe was forfeited: yet they commenced many Suits ſeveral years, to weary out the ſaid <hi>Eyres,</hi> as he was a Priſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner: and alſo commenced a Suit againſt the ſaid <hi>Eyres,</hi> and <hi>Cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cot Chambre</hi> of <hi>Minmore,</hi> who did pretend to be Heir Male to the Eſtate, according to the tenour of Young <hi>Chambre's</hi> Will of <hi>Carnow:</hi> And in the year 1657. all the Suits of the Earl of <hi>Strafford,</hi> and his Agents, came to a full hearing: and after five days debate, from morning to night, before Chancellor <hi>(Steel)</hi> who did then Judge, that the Inheritance might belong to the Earl of <hi>Strafford;</hi> becauſe of the fine and recovery paſt, although it were ſurreptitiouſly gained; and the Heir Male went forth of the Court, and refuſed to make out his Title; but the Court Judged that the Leaſe of 200 years did belong to <hi>William Eyre,</hi> in the right of his Wife; and therefore did diſmiſs the Counteſs of <hi>Carlile,</hi> and the Earl of <hi>Strafford,</hi> and all his Agents, with their Suits, that had been four or five years ſtanding in ſeveral Courts; and did declare, that the ſaid <hi>Eyres</hi> ſhould be kept ſtill in Poſſeſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, in the right of his Wife (the Leaſe of 200 years belonging unto him.)</p>
            <p>Whereupon the Earl of <hi>Strafford</hi>'s Agents produced the before-mentioned Act of Parliament, for the ſtrengthening of defective Titles, upon his Majeſty's Commiſſion of Grace of 400 and odd Mannours (amongſt which) <hi>Shelelah,</hi> and <hi>Chambres</hi> Eſtate, was foyſted in, with a defective Title; upon which Chancellor <hi>Steel</hi> deferred his Jubgement, till the next Term, expecting the ſaid <hi>Eyres,</hi> and his Wifes Croſs-Bill, would come to a hearing.</p>
            <p>By the next Term the Earl of <hi>Strafford,</hi> and all his Agents put in a Plea to the ſaid <hi>Eyres,</hi> and his Wifes Bill, renouncing all Titles, and Claims whatſoever, declared by the ſaid Bill. And did challenge the Eſtate, by the Act of Parliament for ſtrengthen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:180573:7"/>defective Titles; upon which, though it never had the Royal Aſſent, nor was Recorded Judge <hi>Steel</hi> made a Decree, that the Earl of <hi>Strafford</hi> ſhould enjoy the Poſſeſſion of the Eſtate, not up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on any Title, but only by that Act; and declares in his Decree, there is nothing to be conſidered but that: That is, whether it be a defective Title or not, and gave the Earl of <hi>Strafford</hi> Poſſeſſion, till he was outed by due courſe of Law, or farther order of the Court: And did publickly blame <hi>Eyres</hi>'s Counſel, for not bring<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing his Croſs-Bill to hearing, with the Earl of <hi>Strafford's</hi> Suits; and told them that there was ſpeaking of a Will, and an Inquiſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, to prove that the Eſtate was no defective Title; and he did believe there were ſuch things: but they had not appeared Judici<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ally before him, and adviſed the ſaid <hi>Eyres</hi> to Appeal to a Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament, who would undoubtedly do him right in the thing, which he being of an Inferiour Court, had not power to do.</p>
            <p>But the ſaid <hi>Eyres</hi> being, at that time, a Priſoner by <hi>Cromwel</hi>'s order, for oppoſing the death of the late King aforeſaid, could not look after his buſineſs: And was not releaſed, until <hi>Richard Cromwel</hi> was turned out, and <hi>Ludlow</hi> ſent over by the Long-parliament in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to <hi>Ireland:</hi> And within half a year afterwards was made Priſoner again for this occaſion (as followeth) His Majeſty being to be Proclaimed in <hi>Ireland</hi> in the year 1660. on the 18th. of <hi>May,</hi> the aforeſaid <hi>Eyres</hi>'s Wife, deſired that ſhe might rejoyce with her Tenants for the Reſtauration of His Majeſty on the day aforeſaid; and invited ſix or ſeven hundred People to Feaſt, and ordered the ſaid <hi>Eyres</hi>'s Servants to carry ten Wain-load of Wood to a Hill, to make a great Bone-fire.</p>
            <p>But the ſubtilty of his Adverſaries who were in Poſſeſſion of his Eſtate prevented it, that they might the more craftily prevent the ſaid <hi>Eyres</hi> for Appealing to the Parliament in <hi>Ireland</hi> for re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>covering the Leaſe of 200 years aboveſaid: And to that purpoſe, imploying a particular Agent, one <hi>Floid</hi> a <hi>Welſh-man,</hi> to pry into the ſaid <hi>Eyres</hi>'s Actions; he brought fained complaints againſt
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:180573:7"/>him (whereof one was that if they did not fetch the ſaid <hi>Eyres</hi> away before the 18th day, he would be the head of a great Army to oppoſe the coming in of the King; whereupon immediately the Counſel of State ſent five Troops of Horſe and took the ſaid <hi>Eyres</hi> out of his Bed, and carryed him Priſoner to <hi>Dublin</hi> Caſtle, where he was moſt cruelly handled for ſometime: afterwards hurried (from Priſon to Priſon) above Ten years ſpace, and ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>times neither Meat nor Drink ſuffered to come at him, but what was given in by ſtealth at a hole made under the door for the Cat to go in and out: And the Marſhal being demanded by the Priſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners and others, the reaſon of ſo great Cruelty afflicted upon the ſaid <hi>Eyres,</hi> his Anſwer was, that his Command was ſo ſtrick that he did not dare to do otherwiſe; And did declare often that he had an Order to Starve the ſaid <hi>Eyres:</hi> At which time, all perſons whatſoever were prohibited for coming at him. And his Wife was not ſuffered to come to him, yet at the ſame time ſome were admitted to ſerve him with <hi>Subpena</hi>'s, to anſwer a Bill in Chancery, through the Combination of <hi>Alixander Temple,</hi> and the now Earl of <hi>Straffords</hi> Agents: And for Contempt to the Court, Chancel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lor <hi>Huſtes</hi> grants an Injunction, and turns the ſaid <hi>Eyres</hi> Wife and his Family out of doors of the <hi>Rannalaws</hi> too, and they had ut<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terly Periſhed if good people had not Relieved them, although the ſaid <hi>Eyres</hi> his Counſel did proffer his Oath that the ſaid <hi>Eyres</hi> did not make any Contempt, neither was he in any Capacity ſo to do: Upon which Injunction the ſaid <hi>Eyres</hi> and his Family hath been e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver ſince kept out of the Poſſeſſion of the ſaid <hi>Rannalows,</hi> which was pretended to be Purchaſed for the uſe of Mr. <hi>Chambre</hi> afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, which Purchaſe was but a Leaſe of 500 years, and belongs really to the ſaid <hi>Eyres</hi> in the Right of his Wife.</p>
            <p>But by Reaſon of the above-ſaid Combination, The aforeſaid <hi>Eyres,</hi> nor any one of his Family hath not ſince Received one pen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny profit thereof to this day, that he knows of: For his Wife Fainted in the Streets of <hi>Dublin</hi> (for Want and Died) Crying out
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:180573:8"/>her Daughter had broke her Heart ſince <hi>Eyres</hi> Releaſement out of Priſon; And the ſaid <hi>Temple</hi> &amp; his Wife have the Benefit of all that the Earl of <hi>Strafford</hi> was to give for the Inheritance of <hi>Shelala,</hi> ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cept one Five hundred pounds paid to <hi>Chambre</hi> of <hi>Minmore;</hi> al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>though in truth the whole 13 thouſand two hundred pounds which was to be given for <hi>Shelela,</hi> did belong to <hi>William Eyre</hi> in Right of his Wife as a Chattle (as ith hath been often declared by all the Judges in <hi>Ireland,</hi> for that there was no Land Purchaſed in Mr. <hi>Chambre</hi>'s Life time: And the Judges did farther Declare, That what ever they Pay of the Purchaſed Money to any other, than to the ſaid <hi>Eyres,</hi> they paid it in their own wrong) which cauſed the now Earl of <hi>Strafford</hi> to take a Bond of the ſaid <hi>Temple,</hi> of twenty thouſand pounds to ſave him harmleſs from the ſaid <hi>Eyres,</hi> which that will not, nor cannot do (if Juſtice may be had) For Mr. <hi>Chambre</hi>'s Daughter had a Seelected Portion of two thouſand pounds, given her by her Fathers Will, though now they would make her Heir of All.</p>
            <p>Oſerve Mr. <hi>Chambers</hi> gave all his Lands to his Heirs Male, after the Death of his Wife, and to <hi>Calcot Chambers</hi> of <hi>Minmore,</hi> and his Heirs-Male; And that the Earl of <hi>Strafford</hi> at the hearing of Cauſe, Renounced all his Titles to Mr. <hi>Chambers</hi> Eſtate upon which the Inheritance Remains in the ſaid <hi>Eyres</hi> Wife, as well as the Leaſe of two hundred years, he having one onely Child by her.</p>
            <p>For <hi>Calcot Chambre</hi> of <hi>Minmore</hi> ſells to the ſaid <hi>Eyres</hi> his Wife and her then Husband for five hundred pounds by a Deed perfect<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed under his hand and Seal, neer a year after the death of <hi>Cham<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bre</hi> of <hi>Carnow:</hi> Whatever was given in that Will, or by any o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Grant whatſoever to the ſaid <hi>Chambre</hi> of <hi>Minmore;</hi> And therefore that <hi>Chambre</hi> of <hi>Minmore</hi> hath no Right to the Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſes.</p>
            <p>The ſaid <hi>Eyres</hi> ſeeing the Cruelty uſed to him and his Wife, and Family in his Impriſonment, brought himſelf to a Tryal ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>time
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:180573:8"/>ſince in <hi>Ireland</hi> by a <hi>Habe as Corpus,</hi> and was cleared by pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lick Proclamation by the Judges of the <hi>Kings-Bench:</hi> But imme<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>diately, before he was clear of the Priſon, there came an Order to another Marſhall, more cruel than the other was, to take him in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to his Cuſtody, and alſo an Order of High Treaſon: And fo four years and upwards he was brought to the Bar twice a Term, that he might know what this High Treaſon was; but the Attorney General put it off from time to time, inſomuch that the Judges de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clared in open Court, It would light heavy ſomewhere at laſt, in keeping a man ſo long in Priſon after he was cleared by Law. But His Majeſty and Counſel being Informed of the Cru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>elty uſed to the ſaid <hi>Eyres,</hi> granted an Order, That he ſhould have the Benefit of the Law: Upon which Order the Judges brought him upon Tryal; and finding nothing come againſt him, Cleared him the Second time by Proclamation. Which Troubles (he fears purpoſely occaſioned) have been the only Cauſe why he had not ſooner made his Addreſs for Relief.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>
                  <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>pon the Whole Matter Obſerve;</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="1">1. That <hi>Calcot Chambre</hi> the Younger being Entituled not only to the Inheritance, but alſo diſtinctly to the Leaſe of 200 years (which could not be drowned by the Diſcent, becauſe it was to operate to other Intents afterwards, as Payment of Debts, Lega<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cies, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>) And he by his Will having expreſsly given all his Chattels (wherein ſuch Leaſe is included to his Wife, whom al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſo he made Executrix) <hi>Eyres,</hi> by Inter-Marrying with her, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>come, and is Lawfully Entituled thereunto: Nor could the Truſtees Legally Aſſigne it to any, without ſhe and her Husband had Conſented and Joyned therein.</p>
            <p n="2">2. That there appears only 500 <abbr>
                  <hi>ll.</hi>
               </abbr> paid by the Earl, or his A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gents, for this Vaſt Eſtate: out of which the preſent Earl, (though Ordered to the Contrary in the year 1661. till the Title were cleared) has made 3000 <abbr>
                  <hi>ll.</hi>
               </abbr> 
               <hi>per Annum</hi> ever ſince, meerly of Wood growing thereupon.</p>
            <p n="3">
               <pb n="16" facs="tcp:180573:9" rendition="simple:additions"/>
3. That the Earl, his Truſtees, or Agents can pretend no Title but by the Act of Parliament, becauſe they have diſclaimed all others on Record.</p>
            <p n="4">4. That ſuch pretended Act never had the Royal Aſſent: And was obtained on a moſt falſe Suggeſtion; the Premiſes being ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver any Defective Title, as by Inquiſition upon Record doth ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pear.</p>
            <p n="5">5. How tortiouſly, and by what Practiſes all the Pretenſes of Right and Poſſeſſion were obtained; and that there is no Declara<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of Uſes on the ſaid Fine and Recovery by young <hi>Chambre.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Laſtly,</hi> How long the ſaid <hi>William Eyres</hi> has been kept out of ſuch his Right; What ſevere Impriſonments and Hardſhips, (chiefly, as he has good grounds to believe, on this occaſion) he has ſuffered, and to what Extremities he is Reduced; with many other ſad Circumſtances, which will appear to the Judicious, in Reading this his Fore-going Caſe: The Truth whereof he is ready to make appear in every Particular: And yet (had he not been in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>forced by the unanſwerable Impulſes of Neceſſity, after all other O<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vertures were diſpiſed, though offer'd with the greateſt Reſpect) he ſhould not have thus Expoſed the ſame, leſt he ſhould ſeem to ſwound the Memory of the Dead, or the Honour of the Living; Both which are much contrary to the Innocence of his Intentions, whoſe Deſign herein is only to ſet forth matter of Fact; without Aggravations, or unbeſeeming Reflections: And he humbly hopes, ſince His Majeſty in his late Gracious Speech to both Houſes has given the World freſh Aſſurances of his great Zeal for the Preſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vation of Property; It may not be unſeaſonable for this poor Complainant to make his Addreſſes to His Majeſty; and that moſt High and Honourable Court, in whoſe Power only it lies to Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lieve him, For the Reſtitution of his Juſt Rights, ſo long deteyn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed from him.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>William Eyres.</signed>
            </closer>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
